

FARES ABOU JAMRA
GENRAL MANAGER

PROFILE

Business-driven General Manager with 24 years of experience, in Hotel / furnished apartments & resort business throughout front office, operation, and quality management: Forward-thinking leader with expertise in setting goals, quality standards and taking initiatives which lead to quick and efficient attainment of objectives including Revenue increase, Customer Retention, and Operation net profit growth.

A determined, visionary good planning abilities and interpersonal communication strengths, who drive people towards organization strategic goals and focus on overseeing financial, personnel and operational facets. Effectively balance targets with resources and optimize long-term success and Orchestrate optimal resource utilization to handle expected operational needs, satisfy stakeholders, and meet shareholders expectations & targets.

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL MANAGER

THE STAY FURNISHED APARTMENTS (DBAYEH – LEBANON) NOVEMBER 2017 TO JUNE 2021

- Organize budgets, oversee P&Ls and achieve margin targets consistently to stay on track with growth plans.
- Prepare and present organization annual Operating Budget, Marketing
 & Sales Plan and Capital Budget.
- ✓ Plan and organize Successful pre-opening tasks: recruitment, OS&E, project management, quality, Fire safety
- ✓ Works within approved budget, to develop and implement cost saving measures, increase profits and revenue.
- ✓ Implements high standards for all aspects of health and safety, loss prevention and privacy protection.
- ✓ Develop and maintain relationships with stakeholders, customers and suppliers through continual communication and business plan review.
- Evaluate suppliers by assessing quality, timeliness and compliance of deliveries to maintain tight cost controls and maximize business operational efficiency.
- ✓ Ensure that monthly financial outlooks for Rooms, Food & Beverage, Admin & General, on target and accurate.
- Oversee and manage all departments and working closely with their managers on daily basis.
- ✓ Provide effective leadership to hotel teams, driving them towards organization strategy.

DIRECTOR OF ROOMS

AL BUSTAN HOTEL & SPA (BEIT MERY-LEBANON)

APRIL 2017 TO NOVEMBER 2017

- ✓ Hires, trains, assigns and supervises the Rooms Division Management staff, conducts performance evaluations, coaches and counsels' employees when necessary.
- ✓ Implements effective control of operating expenses and labor costs among all Rooms Division departments to ensure profitability, e.g. budgeting, forecasting purchasing specifications, room's inventory controls, etc.
- ✓ Manage quality assurance program, including on-site evaluations, internal audits and customer surveys.
- ✓ Works within approved budget, develops and implements cost saving measures; contributes to profits and revenue.
- ✓ Plans and/or administers training and develops programs within the department which will provide well-trained employees at all levels.
- ✓ Analyzes information concerning the Rooms Division operation such as daily room rates, operating expenses and labor costs.

GENERAL MANAGER

- ✓ Handle guest complaints, resolve them timely, and implement proactive solutions for major problems.
- ✓ Reviews and approves all Rooms Division purchase orders.
- Compiles and directs the preparation of all Rooms Division reports including but not limited to the annual and monthly Rooms Division forecasts.

OPERATIONS MANAGER

PRINCESSA HOTEL (JOUNIEH-LEBANON)

MARCH 2016 TO MARCH 2017

- Maximize productivity and management systems by establishing specific goals and managing operations.
- ✓ Built, supervise and mentor teams and leaders in receiving and inbound operations.
- ✓ Update and publish standard operating procedures (SOPs) using stakeholder, customer and employee input and feedback, resulting in clearer and useful instruction for Clients.
- ✓ Monitor customer feedback to devise business strategies and determine process improvements for better customer experiences.
- ✓ Boost team performance with enhanced employee evaluation processes.
- ✓ Directed day-to-day operations focused on attainment of key business metrics, continuous improvement initiatives.
- ✓ Implement policies and standard operating procedures for continuous improvement.
- Optimize returns and investments by effectively managing all operational functions.
- ✓ Cultivate strong business relationships with clients to increase overall satisfaction and retention rates.
- ✓ Set, enforced and optimized internal policies to maintain efficiency and responsiveness to demands.
- ✓ Conduct regular operations team meeting with the entire HOD daily / weekly to discuss routine operational matters, sales targets, GSTS feedback / RSTS feedbacks and action taken for service recovery.
- ✓ Inspect all departments with their respective Manager's for cleanliness, ambience, service readiness, staff grooming & hospitality culture.
- Evaluate suppliers by assessing quality, timeliness and compliance of deliveries to maintain tight cost controls and maximize business operational efficiency.
- ✓ Handle complaints, and oversee the service recovery procedures

GENERAL MANAGER

QUALITY & BUSINESS EXCELLENCE MANAGER

GLORIA HOTELS (DUBAI, UAE)

NOVEMBER 2011 TO JANUARY 2016

- Maintain high standard of workmanship by using only approved data, materials, tools and test equipment.
- ✓ Identify and help resolve non-conforming service issues.
- Develop checklists to coordinate inspections with departmental managers.
- ✓ Achieve and maintain Go Green certification for continuous 5 years from Green Globe.
- ✓ Earned 3 Guest Experience Awards 2014: Holiday check 5.2/6, Booking.com 8.2 and Hotels.com 8.8.
- ✓ Optimize Cost optimization of AED 2M YOY without compromising on quality: AMC contracts: -19%, Rooms -3% and F&B -5%
- Develop and implement an effective quality control procedure to cover all areas of the Hotel property.
- Coordinates with all Heads of Department to facilitate the provision of proper quality assurance implementation.
- ✓ Reviews all guest comments (Rooms / F&B / online sources) and consolidate a weekly report and analysis to the top management.
- ✓ Establishes and updates Hotel property's quality specifications and standards. (SOP's Standard of performance)
- ✓ Produces monthly data and analytical reports on the overall quality performance, measuring the same against set standards.
- ✓ Provides the Hotel organization with tools and techniques to enable everyone to achieve their quality objectives.
- ✓ Ensure full compliance to Hotel operating controls, SOP's, policies, procedures and service standards.

ROOM DIVISION MANAGER

POERTEMILIO HOTEL & RESORT (JOUNIEH-LEBANON)

OCTOBER 2009 TO NOVEMBER 2011

FRONT OFFICE MANAGER

RIMAL ROTANA HOTEL (DUBAI, UAE)

MARCH 2008 TO AUGUST 2009

FRONT OFFICE MANAGER

DHOW PALACE HOTEL (DUBAI, UAE)

DECEMBER 2005 TO FEBRUARY 2008

GENERAL MANAGER

EDUCATION

SUPERIOR TECHNICAL

MAJOR: HOTEL & RESTAURANT MANAGEMENT FRANCEL COLLEGE - LEBANON 1996 TO 1999

TECHNICAL BACCALAUREATE

MAJOR: COMMERCIAL SCIENCE

CIT - LEBANON 1992 TO 1994

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native English: Fluent French: Fluent

KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS

- ✓ Budget administration
- ✓ Coaching and mentoring
- ✓ Operations management
- ✓ Effective leader
- ✓ Staff training/development
- ✓ Budgeting and forecasting
- ✓ Audit Reporting

- ✓ Cost reduction strategies
- √ Financial Management
- √ Report generation
- Knowledge of quality systems
- ✓ Policy reinforcement

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Mobile: +971 58 9466997

Email: faresaboujamra@gmail.com

Nationality: Lebanese

Visa Status: Visit valid till 29/10/21
Date Of Birth: 10 December 1975
Marital Status: Married with one child

Driving License: Lebanese & UAE

Location: Discovery gardens, Dubai, UAE

GENERAL MANAGER

ACHIEVEMENTS

- ✓ Technical Software knowledge and utilization: Fidelio Front Office, Brilliant, PMS & IDS Fortunes, QEMS, Navision, Orient
- ✓ Achieve KPI of 85% occupancy all over the year.
- Create SMART KPI's (Specific, Measurable, Attainable, Relevant, and Time-Bound) to improve on-time delivery, resolve customer issues and increase safety overall.
- ✓ Spearhead employee engagement program, to retain 5% more employees, reducing the annual personnel turnover.
- ✓ Improve customer satisfaction ratings: by 40% within 6 months and obtain 4 stars out of 5 in customer satisfaction scores on Trip advisor. Reduced number of guest complaints by 75% percent.
- ✓ Maintain a guest satisfaction rating of greater than 88% on Market Matrix
- ✓ Led successful environmental committee to reduce waste, energy and water consumption.
- ✓ Create training processes for 8 separate departments.
- ✓ Exceed associate job placement goal by 40% by implementing thorough training and development program assessments.
- ✓ Complete an average of 200 request orders a day with quality management system.

CERTIFICATIONS

- ✓ First Aide Certificate
- ✓ Fire Warden Certificate
- ✓ Presentation Skills Certificate
- Manager of Quality/Organizational Excellence Certificate from ASQ(American Society of quality)

TRAINING

- ✓ MPP Training (Managing people performance)
- ✓ MED Training (Managing employee development)
- ✓ OJT Training Program (On-job Training)
- ✓ Zodiac Training Program
- ✓ Train the trainer
- ✓ QEMS Training Program (Quality Engineering Management System)
- ✓ Emotional Intelligence Training
- ✓ Competency Models Training
- ✓ The Core Principles of Leadership